

RESEARCH ENGINEER

250 S. Clinton St. Ste. 510, Syracuse, NY 13202

Profile

Enthusiastic engineer with extensive quality assurance and automation experience in a wide assortment of operational environments.

Skills

Technical Skills Continuous integration, automated testing, system administration, system integration and troubleshooting

Programming Languages C++, C, C#, Java, SQL, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, Perl, Python, Bash, LaTeX

Applications Git, Gitlab, Redmine, Apache Web Server, Apache Traffic Server, Wordpress, MySQL, MS Office, Wireshark

Development Platforms Linux, QNX, Windows, Android

Other Skills Strong verbal and written communication skills, excellent problem solving and troubleshooting skills,

comfortable with both individual and collaborative work

Work Experience

Exception Technologies, LLC

Syracuse, NY

RESEARCH ENGINEER September 2016 - Present

- Developed continuous integration system for a proprietary symbolic execution platform using Gitlab CI and Cucumber.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Developed new plugins for VM introspection for the symbolic execution platform using C++}.$
- · Debugged and troubleshot the symbolic execution platform for various test cases and execution environments.
- Researched virtual hard disk formats for a project involving the gemu virtualization platform.
- Researched the current state of the art in uncertainty quantification.

National Grid Syracuse, NY

SENIOR CIP Analyst March 2015 - September 2016

- Created a custom Linux environment for use on substation computers to run fault collection and analysis.
- Wrote Python scripts to monitor the health and operation of substation computers.
- · Worked with the developers of the Wavewin software to create extensions for monitoring substation equipment and retrieving data from it.
- Developed configurations for many different types of network hardware from RuggedCom (Siemens), Schweitzer and GarrettCom.

Assured Information Security

Rome, NY

ASSOCIATE ENGINEER November 2012 - March 2015

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Debugged and tested the Secure View multi-domain desktop virtualization software written primarily in C++.}$
- Maintained the build system for SecureView and developed the build/release process.
- Debugged the Javascript front-end for SecureView and oversaw the team of subcontractors tasked with fixing the issues.
- Integrated the Apache Traffic Server with custom software designed to offload analysis of web traffic to a highly optimized parallel computing application implemented in OpenCL.

Lockheed Martin Syracuse, NY

Systems Integration and Test Engineer

May 2009 - November 2012

- Performed formal software and hardware testing of radar and sonar systems.
- Developed an in-depth knowledge of radar and sonar systems in order to effectively troubleshoot and isolate problems.
- Completed various network design and configuration tasks on RuggedCom, Cisco and 3Com hardware.
- Configured several Linux/UNIX variants on many different types of hardware, built and debugged Linux kernels and drivers.
- Designed and implemented a Remote Installation Procedure for the system using various Linux tools and bash scripts to automate its installation aboard ships.
- Traveled frequently to various military installations to troubleshoot system problems and support field testing.

Education

Clarkson University Potsdam, NY

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, MINOR IN MATHEMATICS May 2009

JUNE 7, 2017 EXCEPTION TECHNOLOGIES 1